["Moonlight" by L'FREAQ playing]
♪ Paint my wounds, lover... ♪
[sister] My sister Deva loves
really deeply,
but ever since a couple of heartbreaks,
I haven't really seen her
surrender to romance.
I think she's trying
to relearn her heart, in a way.
♪ Ho, oh, don't you want to see me
In the moonlight? ♪
[sister] When people meet Deva,
they are pretty intimidated by her.
She needs someone
who is confident enough in themselves
to embrace her in all her glory.
♪ Ho, oh,
Say you'll never treat me nice... ♪
[sister] She definitely has her guards.
But since Deva's moved to New Orleans,
I have seen her own her sexuality,
and her beauty, and her body.
♪ Ho, oh, don't you recognize me
In the moonlight? ♪
[sister] I'd love to see her have
a joyful, romantic experience
with someone...
where they can completely fall in love
with abandon...
rather than compete for space.
-[chuckles] Hi.
-Hey, how you doing?
-I'm Rueben.
-Good. I'm Deva.
-Nice to meet you. Deva?
-Deva, yeah.
-Okay. You look amazing.
-Thank you.
-Tell me your name one more time. Rueben.
-Rueben.
-It's a pleasure to meet you.
-Cool.
Uh, I think, should we go get a drink?
-Yeah, let's go in.
-Okay.
So, True.
Yes.
It's very nice to meet you.
You look really nice tonight.
Thank you.
I put it all together for this date.
Oh, well.
You look amazing too.
-Thank you.
-No doubt. No doubt.
What's...? Who's...?
I mean, I didn't mean to touch you
or anything like that.
-Ask consent always.
-[laughs]
But it's Ulla Johnson.
She's an amazing designer from New York.
Oh. I'm from New York.
Really? Where?
I'm from Marshall Heights.
I used to live in Harlem.
-No doubt.
-Yeah.
You're definitely from New York
'cause you're like, "No doubt."
-Like, I see you.
-[laughs]
-Thank you.
-[Maria] Hi, are you my date?
Yeah.
-Hi. I'm Maria. Good to meet you.
-Hi.
-Can I hug you?
-I'm Deva. Yeah.
-Devee? Deva.
-Deva.
Maria.
Good to meet you.
You look great.
-You look great.
-Thank you.
Cool.
How are you?
-Doing fine.
-Yeah.
-Had a nice day off.
-Oh, you did?
Yeah, some relaxing porch lunch
-and chilled in the garden.
-Cool.
Nice. Oh!
It's so nice to see you.
I went and got acupuncture
for the first time before I came here.
I'd never done it before.
And I was like, it just,
like, ended up being,
like, right before I had to be here.
Yeah.
-And it was so, like, calming.
-Oh, good. I should have done that.
Right.
I suddenly was so chill,
and I suddenly just got super nervous
when you walked in. [chuckles]
-I already know what I want.
-So do I.
I want a green tea shot.
What is a green tea shot?
Well, I'm trying to drink healthier.
Oh, like actual green tea.
No, it's not actual green tea.
There's, like, Jameson Whiskey, uh...
I think peach schnapps,
um, sour and Sprite.
How is that healthier?
It has a lot of antioxidants.
Which is great for--
In the Sprite or the Jameson?
-What are you drinking?
-I'll have a white Negroni with mezcal.
I'll have a white maroni with mezcal.
Negroni. [laughs]
Did you say maroni?
-That's what you said.
-No, I did not.
-I'll have what she's having.
-Okay.
[laughing]
Tell me a little bit about yourself.
I grew up in Los Angeles.
And I got to the point where I recognized
that the city was going to kill me.
Oh, okay.
-At least spiritually, if not physically.
-Okay.
And I went to New York and...
made something of myself,
and then got tired of New York
and moved here.
Okay.
Are you, um, originally from here?
No.
Originally I am from Hawaii.
Oh. Cool.
So I left and I was in
the Pacific Northwest for a while.
And then I moved to New Zealand...
Mm-hmm.
...for, like, almost seven years.
-So, why did you go to New Zealand?
-Well--
It's like the growth on the neck
of Australia?
-Don't say that. You can't say that.
-I'm sorry.
I have too much New Zealand pride
for that to slide.
When did you move here?
Four years for me in January.
-So whenever that is, 2000--
-Oh. I'm way fresher than you.
-I moved in December.
-You're fresh to death?
-You're super fresh.
-Straight.
-Straight fresh.
-Off the boat.
-No doubt.
[Maria] Why did you come here?
I, uh...
wanted a change of pace.
New York is really challenging to live in,
and also be creative.
-I just put out a record last year.
-Oh, great.
So that's been exciting.
I've spent most of the year touring.
So now you're a singer extraordinaire.
-I mean--
-How did you get into doing that?
When I was a kid I was, like, pretty--
I didn't really fit in.
And it was hard for me to make friends.
There was, like,
some bullying and all those kinds
of things when I was growing up.
And then I just discovered
I really loved making music.
Like, so deeply.
Well, maybe a little later on
I'm gonna have to hear a little something.
-Oh, no.
-If you're open to it.
-No.
-No? I've gotta pay for it?
Yeah, you've gotta pay for it.
That costs money.
-People gotta pay for my stuff, only fair.
-True. What do you do?
I'm a chiropractor.
-Oh, my God. We gotta talk.
-[chuckles]
Often times I'm on the other side
of the bar, where he is.
-Oh, you bartend?
-Yeah.
I managed to get some properties.
So I live off off of rental income.
Wow. That's amazing.
So I work for a ballet company.
I make costumes for them.
My grandmother was a seamstress,
and she would make all of my mom
and her sisters' clothes.
Whoa.
So after she died I feel like I, like,
inherited her sewing juju somehow.
Wow.
I mean, New Orleans
is such a costume town, you know?
Like, anytime you go out,
like, every weekend,
-it's like, you know, looks.
-I love it.
-I love it. I love it.
-[laughs]
-Well, cheers. Yeah.
-Cheers, darling.
All right.
Salut. Salut.
-Cheers.
Oh! Careful.
[waiter] Your table's ready
whenever you're ready.
-[Deva] Thank you.
-Follow me.
-Are you ready to eat?
-Yeah. [chuckles]
-How's your drink?
-It's good, yeah.
I love me an old fashioned.
-Thank you. Thank you.
-Awesome.
Thanks. [chuckles]
So...
Tell me about your artwork.
[Maria] Oh.
-I just had an art show, actually.
-Oh, you did?
Last week. I have a gallery show
up on Julia Street.
-What's your last name?
-Sandhammer.
I know your stuff.
-No, you don't.
-Yeah.
-Do you make eye masks?
-I do that too.
-Yeah.
-Those are awesome.
-[laughs]
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
I bought one for my roommate.
-Cool. You bought one? [laughs]
-Yeah.
Yeah, totally.
That's cool.
Good evening, guys, my name is Scott.
I'll take care of you tonight. Welcome.
-Here you are. Very welcome.
-Thank you.
I would like to try the olive-cured duck.
[True] Perfect. Good choice.
-Could I get the redfish, please?
-[Scott] Redfish, excellent.
No worries.
When's your birthday?
-I'm an Aries, unfortunately.
-Okay.
Why unfortunately?
Not a lot of people like us.
I'm cool with Aries.
-So that's cool. That's good to know.
-Yeah.
-How about yourself? Capricorn.
-I'm a Capricorn.
You're on the heels of Scorpios,
who are like the bane of my existence.
[chuckles]
No. It goes Scorpio,
Sagittarius, then Capricorn.
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Oh, my God.
That looks beautiful.
It does look beautiful, so enjoy.
[Deva] So, you share food?
What's the point
of ordering different things--?
-Some people don't like to share food.
-Some people kick puppies.
-And... I'm just saying--
-Okay, where did you...
-I don't.
-...where did we go from food sharing
to kicking puppies?
I'm not saying that people
that don't share food kick puppies.
I'm just saying they're more likely to.
[Maria] I really like my family,
for the most part.
They all accept me,
-even though I'm a weirdo.
-Oh, tell me about that.
Are you, like, the black sheep?
Yeah, yeah, pretty much. I--
Is it because you date women
or is it because...
-It's just because...
-...you're an artist?
...I've always been-- My uncle's like,
"You're into art stuff."
'Cause he's from Boston.
"You're into that art stuff."
I have family in that Boston area too.
And it's very much like work,
gotta have the house, the car,
the kids.
-Yes.
-So...
So, yeah, I've had a little bit
of pressure surrounding that.
-Yeah.
-[Brooke] There was one other person
who I dated briefly in New Orleans.
[Deva] Mm-hmm.
Although they identified as a trans man.
-Okay.
-So that was different.
You know, there's, like, so much nuance
in, like, how people identify, like...
What I'm just trying to do
is meet people where they're at
and, like, not make any judgments
and really just support them, you know?
[Deva] How long were you married for?
I was with her for eight and a half years.
Can I ask why you guys got divorced?
-She wanted to be kept.
-Oh, okay.
She wasn't saying to me,
"I don't want to work
so that I can stay home and cook
and clean and bear your children."
It was, "I don't wanna work
because I wanna live a fabulous life,
and wear lots of new clothes,
and go to restaurants,
and you pay for it.
How do you feel dating a strong woman?
-I'm attracted to that.
-Yeah?
Yeah.
I think a lot of people
are really intimidated by me.
Don't find it...
intimidating,
and a lot of times behind that...
strongness is a sensitivity and...
vulnerability.
[both laughing]
I think...
everybody on the planet is crazy.
And crazy breaks down into two categories.
You have homicidal crazy
and suicidal crazy.
You know, the best you can hope for
is that you don't have a partner
that will harm you.
Okay, I'm trying
to follow you here, but...
I think I need a little more...
[chuckles] explanation.
Yeah, I've had a lot of, um...
trying relationships.
What about you?
What is your relationship background?
I was with somebody for,
like, six and a half years.
And that's probably the most
influential relationship I've ever had.
And it was really challenging
to, like, move past that.
I actually also have, kind of,
fully come to terms
with the fact that I'm interested
in also dating women.
Uh-huh!
When I was younger,
I called myself a lesbian,
but I don't think that that
is accurate at all
because I've dated all genders.
I just like to...
think that we're all people.
-Yeah.
-And maybe it doesn't matter
-what our genders are.
-Yeah.
I agree.
This, like, being a woman is weird.
I do have, like, my qualms about it.
But, like, I haven't had to,
like, question myself
in terms of, like, body dysmorphia
or, like, you know,
I have my things where I'm, like,
yeah, sometimes you do feel like you're
crushed under the boot of capitalism
or, like, you're just like a cog
in the machine.
-Yeah.
-Mm.
How long does it take
for you to feel like...
you know, maybe this is...
someone I can...
see myself being with?
It really depends. Uh...
What about you?
In my head, I feel like most of the time,
-I know pretty quickly.
-Mm-hmm.
-Um...
-[chuckles]
-I've-- Okay. Yeah.
-[laughs]
I'll leave it at that.
Okay. [laughs]
Cool.
Tell me about your music.
Well,
I'm glad you asked.
Um, I actually recorded
for the very first time
when I was probably like five
or six with my dad.
-And--
-Was your dad a musician?
Yeah.
Anyone that I would know?
Probably.
If you listen to American blues
and roots music,
then you would know who my dad is.
Who's your dad?
Taj Mahal.
[laughing]
Seriously?
Okay.
[both laughing]
No doubt.
-That's amazing.
-Yeah.
-So...
-Okay.
...it's, like, kind of a weird thing
to talk about, but...
-So--
-My dad's also Taj Mahal.
-Now, that would be weird.
-Okay, that would be really weird.
And I'd be like,
"Check, please. It's time to go."
I think it's amazing,
just from appreciating music,
that, like, your dad is who he is,
but you also are who you are
in terms of, like, your voice
and your natural ability.
Like, I can't sing for shit.
Like, at all...
And now I fully expect you to sing.
I mean, there's karaoke going on later
if you wanna come join.
You are speaking my language!
-Oh, my God.
-Yeah.
Is it gonna be, like, some
Andrew Lloyd Webber shit? Are you gonna--?
-Like some theater shit? No.
-Yes!
[both laughing]
No fuckin' way.
You're out of your mind.
Okay, well,
let's go grab a drink, shall we?
-Okay, no doubt. For sure.
-Okay.
-Do you feel like we should?
-I do.
-Oh, great.
-All right.
-Let's go.
-Let's go. I'm sorry.
-I don't wanna rush you.
-No, I don't need that anymore.
It's all right. I'm done.
[chuckles]
-To the bar.
-[chuckles]
[Touré] So are you ready
for that karaoke challenge?
Yes.
All right, so that means
I possibly might see you again?
Like, in the future, that's a possibility?
Yeah, I think so.
All right. All right. All right.
Cool. No doubt.
Um...
So, uh... [laughs]
You're so smooth here.
You're really, really winning.
[chuckles] I know... I never...
never get points
on the smooth tip for sure.
Like, I never said that I had game
in any capacity.
You better get some.
[both laughing]
Earlier you were talking
about your sexuality
and how you had discovered an interest
in dating women as well as men.
Would you call yourself bisexual?
I don't really deal in labels.
Not really...
-my thing, but...
-Right.
What about you?
I only date bisexual women.
-Oh, interesting.
-Yeah.
Why do you think that is?
Because...
Oh...
my attraction to women
is such an integral part of who I am,
and how I think and how I see the world...
that if you don't...
also find women as beautiful
and sexy as I do--
I have never heard that.
It's very interesting.
I have to come to your bar. Here's a test.
-You have to make me a drink.
-What would you want?
Well, if I had to order...
I would order a white Negroni
with mezcal.
-Really?
-Yes.
-All right. I got--
-So be ready.
Heard, got you. Yeah.
White Negroni with mezcal.
-Okay, don't forget it.
-[chuckles]
Got you.
-All right, I'm ready for you.
-Awesome. [chuckles]
Okay.
-Shall we...?
-Yeah, no doubt.
-Okay.
-All right.
[exhales]
[both laughing]
-[Deva] Whoa, don't pull me over.
-[blows raspberry, laughs]
-You're so silly.
-[continues laughing]
You're silly.
-[exhales] Is this good?
-Yeah.
Okay.
Cool.
But I've had so much fun.
It's really nice to talk
to somebody who I feel like
I don't have to explain too much to,
and that I already know that they
kind of understand what I mean,
and that I understand them as well.
It's really cool.
-Yes.
-Yeah, cheers.
-Cheers.
-[chuckles]
I mean, you're beautiful.
Like you are killing it.
-You're, like, really...
-Oh.
Thank you.
See, now you've made me all embarrassed.
-I like to have everything on the table.
-Okay.
Oh, oh, what are you doing?
-I just wanna give you a hug.
-Okay.
-And a kiss.
-On my cheek.
Okay.
I'm not a kiss-on-the-first-date
kind of girl.
How did this feel for you? Was it cool?
Did you have a good time?
-Oh, my God, it was so cool.
-Yeah.
-It was so good getting to hang with you.
-Yeah, you too.
-Yeah.
-Super.
Um...
Okay, well, I just...
I had so much fun,
but I don't think
we are each other's type.
-Okay.
-Yeah, I think we can definitely hang out.
All right.
-Nice to have a new friend in New Orleans.
-Yes.
Well, thank you. I'm gonna give you a hug.
All right, baby.
[both chuckling]
-It's all good. All good.
-Oh, my God.
I hope you have a good night,
and you get home safe.
-You too.
-Okay.
All right, bye.
Bye.
[Rueben] Are we gonna keep in touch?
Um, yeah, I think if you...
if you can, I think you should find me
on my Instagram.
-Really?
-Yes.
Really?
-All right.
-Okay.
-I guess this is good night.
-Yeah.
-Thank you so much.
-All right.
Have a wonderful night.
-You too as well.
-Okay.
-All right.
-[chuckles]
-All right, have a good night.
-All right, good night.
Bye.
I have interesting stories. I think I have
some really interesting stories.
-Like-- I be like...
-Like what?
[laughs]
-That was awesome.
-It's all right. You saved it, recovered.
Well, like, a lot of my adventures
are a little bit off the beaten cuff.
-You know?
-Right.
Lived in the Dominican Republic a year.
Can you speak Spanish?
Like, only when I'm drunk.
-[laughs]
-You speak, like, rum Spanish.
Yeah, it's like,
you know, yeah, it's like slang
more so than anything that you need to...
-Ah.
-[chuckles]
-Let's put that glass over there--
-Good save.
So slick.
-[laughs]
-Smooth operator.
[continues laughing]
I feel like...
we should commemorate this.
So I feel like we should make a wish
-into this pond.
-Can I think for a second?
Yes, but here's your penny.
-I got a penny! [laughs]
-Yes!
-I'm into it.
-Okay.
-Did you think of your wish already?
-Not yet. I'll tell you when I have it.
Are you gonna tell me yours after?
-No, I'll just tell you when I have it.
-I'm not gonna tell you mine either.
One, two, three.
Yay.
[both laughing]
-[gasps] Oh, my gosh.
-[chuckles]
Okay, well, I...
feel like maybe we should finish our drink
and then share a Lyft home.
-Yeah.
-Okay. Cool.
-Yes.
-Um...
-I--
-What?
Can I kiss you now?
Yes.
[chuckles]
Wow. Okay.
Seat belt. Safety first, for sure.
-Yes.
-All right.
No doubt.
I don't know.
My seat belt game is never on point,
but...
[exhales]
Yes.
How's your night been so far?
It's been fun.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Yeah, I think, I was, like, myself,
like, pleasantly surprised
by the evening, you know?
It's great to meet, like, someone
that's also been from New York.
-Oh, yeah.
-Also, like...
had, uh...
so much trajectory that I have.
-So if anything...
-Yeah.
uh, I would love to be, like, someone
that you, like, hang out with.
Um...
Where do you wanna go next?
I'm ready to go home.
You ready to go home? All right.
-Yeah.
-Cool.
Cool.
Another challenge for me is that,
in addition to...
uh, finding women who are bisexual,
is that I'm poly as well.
-Oh, okay. I could've pegged you for that.
-Yeah.
I mean, my poly dynamic is myself
and some number of women,
but no other men.
So if you're in a poly relationship,
can the woman that you date
date other men?
No.
Don't you think that that's,
like, a bit one-sided?
-No.
-You don't think that that's sexist?
No.
[driver] Well, this is your stop, sir.
Okay.
It was very, very interesting
and enlightening.
And I feel like
I will see you again very soon.
[chuckles]
-Okay, well, have a great night.
-You too.
[car door closes]
Wow.
[driver] Here's your stop.
Thank you.
-I hope you have a great night.
-You too.
-I had fun.
-I'll see you soon.
-Okay.
-I'm out.
Bye.
[car door closes]
[driver] All right, we're here.
-Oh. Oh, look, we're at my house.
-Oh.
Oh, look.
-[clicks tongue] Sad.
-Um...
-I have your number.
-Yeah.
Can I...
give you another kiss?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
Okay.
Have a good night.
-You too. Have a good night.
-Okay.
Bye.
Okay.
[chuckles]
[exhales]
["Fire" by Deva Mahal playing]
♪ Long ♪
♪ It's been a long time coming ♪
♪ Though it's in the strong ♪
♪ A real strong warning ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Said oh... ♪
Hi.
Look at you. You look so cute.
You look so cute.
So do you.
-Hi.
-How are you?
-How have you been?
-Good.
-Looking...
-[chuckles]
Where should we go?
Uh, I don't know. Let's head up that way.
Okay.
[both laughing]
-Shall we?
-Mm-hmm.
-I'll follow you.
-Okay.
♪ Said oh... ♪
[both chuckling]
[Maria] I have that song in my head
from The Wizard of Oz.
[Deva] Which one?
♪ Said I can't go ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ Any further ♪
♪ And if you only know ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ The darkness inside of me ♪
♪ No, oh ♪